-Hey. -Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
-What are you doing? -I was thinking of moving the couch.
-你在做什麼？ -我想把沙發搬開
Why would you want to do that?
你為什麼要那麼做？
So there'd be a decent place for me to sit?
那樣子我就有好位置可以坐了？
-Rach, there is a decent place. -And your lap does not count.
-瑞秋，你本來就有好位置坐了 -你的大腿不算
-Come on, help me move this. -No, no, no.
-來吧，幫我把它搬開 -不
-No? -No.
-你不要？ -我不要
Rosita does not move.
蘿希塔不想移開
I'm sorry. Rosita? As in..?
對不起，蘿希塔，它是…？
As in "Rosita does not move."
就是「不想動的蘿希塔」
It's just a chair. What's the big deal?
它只是一張椅子 它有什麼大不了的？
It's the exact equal distance from the bathroom to the kitchen...
它到浴室跟到廚房的距離是一樣的…
and it's at an angle where you don't get any glare coming off Stevie.
而且它的角度讓你完全 看不到史提夫的閃光
Stevie the TV?
電視機史提夫？
-Is there a problem? -No.
-有問題嗎？ -沒有
What does he know?
他又知道什麼？
Come on, Rosita. Us chicas gotta stick together.
來吧，蘿希塔 我們這些辣妹得合作才行
You bitch!
你這個臭女人！
The One Where Rosita Dies
本集播出：蘿希塔之死
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Hey, Ross?
嘿，羅斯？
I checked the real estate section.
我看過房地產廣告版
Look at this.
你看這個
Looks like Mom and Dad's house.
看起來好像爸媽的房子
Even has a tree with a broken limb out front.
院子裡的樹 正前方也有根斷掉的樹枝
And the window in the attic...
閣樓的窗戶…
Oh, my God!
喔，我的天啊！
What happened to the window in the attic?
閣樓的窗戶怎麼了？
-I can't believe they're selling it. -And they didn't tell us.
-我不敢相信他們要把它賣掉 -卻沒有告訴我們
What happened to the window in the attic?
閣樓的窗戶怎麼了？
I'll buy you a new one, okay?
我會買張新椅子賠你，好嗎？
We'll go to the store and get you a new chair right now.
我們馬上到店裡去 幫你買一張新椅子
She's not even cold yet.
她還屍骨未寒
Wouldn't Rosita have wanted you to move on?
蘿希塔不希望你繼續過你的日子嗎？
I mean, you know, she did always put your comfort first.
我是說她永遠 把你的幸福放在第一順位
That's true.
沒錯
I can't believe we have to say goodbye to the house we grew up in.
我不敢相信 我們得跟小時候的家說再見
Man, some stranger's gonna be in my room.
天啊，有個陌生人 就要搬進我的房間裡
For 15 years they kept it as a shrine to you.
十五年來，他們把你房間 弄得跟神龕差不多
It's time the velvet ropes came down.
現在一切都該落幕了
They kept your room a while.
他們也保留你房間有一陣子
Please! Dad turned my room into a gym 20 minutes after I moved out.
拜託，我搬出來二十分鐘後 爸就把我的房間變成健身房
I gotta say, a tanning bed and a stack of Victoria's Secret catalogs?
我很懷疑，一張日光浴椅 跟一堆維多利亞秘密的目錄？
Not a gym.
那不是健身房
-Come on. You know they love you. -As much as they love you?
-別這樣，你知道他們愛你 -就跟他們愛你一樣？
They thought she was barren until I was born. It's not my fault.
我沒出生前，他們以為她不會生 那不是我的錯
I hate this year.
我討厭今年
What's wrong with this year?
今年有什麼不對的？
It's February and I've only given two massages...
現在已經是二月 我只接到兩個按摩客人…
and they were both horrible tippers.
而且他們給小費都給得很吝嗇
That was me and Ross.
你是指我跟羅斯
Oh, that's right.
喔，沒錯
If you want some extra cash...
如果你需要錢…
some college friends made good money doing telemarketing.
我大學的朋友 做電話行銷賺了不少錢
It'd be better than the last telephone job I had.
它一定比上次 我做的電話行銷工作還棒
I probably won't have to say "spank" as much.
或許我不必常常說「打我屁股吧」
What?
什麼？
Oh, yeah, like you never called.
對，你從來沒打過那種電話
This is very easy. You read from the script...
這真的很簡單，你只要照著稿子念…
and try to sell as much toner as you can.
試著多賣一點碳粉
Okay, I can do that.
好吧，我辦得到
By the way, I love my office.
對了，我喜歡我的辦公室
-Why don't we do a trial run? -Oh, okay.
-我們為什麼不來練習一下？ -好吧
All right.
好了
Hi, this is Phoebe from Empire Office Supplies.
嗨，我是帝國辦公室文具公司的菲比
-Can I speak to your supply manager? -I'm the supply manager.
-請問總務部經理在嗎？ -我就是總務部經理
I'd like to talk about your toner needs.
我想跟你談談買碳粉的事
We don't need any.
我們不需要碳粉
Okay, sorry to bother you. Bye-bye.
好吧，抱歉打擾你了，再見
Yeah, you're right. This is easy.
你說的對，這真的很容易
Okay. What was wrong with that call?
好吧，那通電話哪裡不對勁呢？
Oh, well, all right.
好吧
No offense, but you were kind of rude.
我沒有惡意，但你的態度真的很不好
They always say they don't need toner. That's okay.
他們永遠都會說 他們不需要碳粉，沒關係
Whatever they say, you can find the answer to it, here in the script.
不管他們說什麼 你都會在稿子裡找到標準解答
So I think you're ready to sell toner.
我想你準備好要賣碳粉了
-Do you have any last questions? -No.
-你還有問題嗎？ -沒有了
Wait, yes, I do have one question:
等一下，對了，我的確有一個問題
What is toner?
什麼是碳粉？
Joey?
喬伊？
Joe?
Full bag?
原封未動？
Beer's still cold.
啤酒還是冰的
Something terrible must have happened here.
這裡一定發生了很可怕的事
Oh, no, no, no!
喔，不…
Stevie, I was never here.
史提夫，我沒來過這裡
-Dad? -I'm here!
-爸？ -我在這裡！
-Hey. -Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
Seems like just yesterday you guys used to come out to watch me work.
感覺上好像以前你們 跑來這裡看我工作的時候
We can't believe you're selling the house.
我們不敢相信你們要賣掉房子
Time for a new family to start here.
也該讓新的家庭 在這裡開始他們的新生活了
I hope their check clears before they find the crack...
我希望在支票兌現前 他們不會發現…
in the foundation and the asbestos in the ceiling.
地基有裂痕，天花板的石棉瓦破了
Let's grab our stuff and get the hell out of here.
我們快把東西拿一拿，離開這裡吧
-Sorry we can't store your things. -Oh, it's okay.
-抱歉我們不能收藏你們的東西 -沒關係
I can't wait to see everything again.
我等不及要再看到那些東西了
I don't know what's down here.
我不知道這裡放了什麼
But there are six or seven Easy-Bake Ovens in the attic.
但閣樓上有六，七箱簡易烘焙烤箱
I used to love to play restaurant.
我以前最喜歡玩開餐廳的遊戲了
Not as much as you loved to play "uncooked batter eater."
但你最愛的還是「吃麵粉糊」
You can't expect a child to wait for a light bulb to cook brownies.
你不能要求小孩子 等著電燈泡把餅乾烤好
So I think your boxes are over here.
我想你的箱子應該都在這裡
Oh, great.
太棒了
Hey...
嘿…
whose cigarettes are these?
這是誰的煙？
I don't know.
我不知道
They must be your mother's.
一定是你媽的
But please, please don't ask her. I'll throw these away.
但求求你別去質問她 我來把煙丟掉
Cool! Dad, my report cards!
酷啊！爸，是我的成績單！
Hey, check this out.
嘿，快來看看
Math, "A." Science, "A." History, "A." Gym...
數學「優等」，自然「優等」 歷史「優等」，體育…
My rock polisher!
我的磨石機！
-Uh-oh. -What?
-慘了 -怎麼了？
You know how the garage floods every spring?
你知道每年春天車庫都會淹水嗎？
How are you ever gonna sell this place?
你要怎麼把房子賣掉？
I think I accidentally used Monica's boxes...
我想我不小心拿摩妮卡的箱子…
to keep the water away from the Porsche.
來擋水，免得保時捷進了水
Oh, no, Dad. Dad?
喔，不，爸，爸？
What the..
搞什麼…
Oh, God. Everything's ruined!
喔，天啊，一切都毀了！
Dad, she's gonna be crushed.
爸，她一定會崩潰的
You don't secretly smoke, do you?
你該不會是偷偷在抽煙吧？
No.
不
So it's just your mother then.
是你媽在抽煙
Hi. This is Phoebe from Empire Office Supplies.
嗨，我是帝國辦公室文具公司的菲比
Can I speak to your supply manager, please?
請問總務部經理在嗎？
Earl. Thanks.
厄爾，謝謝
Hi, Earl. This is Phoebe from Empire Office Supplies.
嗨，厄爾，我是帝國辦公室 文具公司的菲比
I'd like to talk to you about your toner needs.
我想跟你談談買碳粉的事
I don't need any toner.
我不需要碳粉
I hear what you're saying, but at our prices, everyone needs toner.
我知道了，但是聽了我們的價格 大家都會想買碳粉
Not me.
我不要
May I ask why?
能請問你為什麼嗎？
You want to know why?
你想知道為什麼？
I surely do.
我真的很想
Okay.
好吧
I don't need any toner...
我不需要碳粉…
because I'm gonna kill myself.
因為我就要自殺了
Is that because you're out of toner?
那是因為你的碳粉用完了嗎？
Okay, so no toner today. Thanks anyway. Bye-bye.
好吧，今天我不需要碳粉 謝謝你，再見
Wait, wait! I can't let you hang up. Just please talk to me.
等一下！我不能讓你掛電話 請你跟我說話
Well...
喔…
I only had one thing to do today.
今天我只需要做一件事
（今天的工作 自殺）
I guess I could push it back.
我猜我能把它延期一下吧
Yeah. Now, why do you want to kill yourself?
好吧，你為什麼要自殺？
I've been working for 10 years now at this...
十年來，我一直在做…
meaningless, dead-end job...
這份沒有意義又沒有前途的工作…
and nobody here even knows that I exist.
辦公室裡的人根本不知道我的存在
Chandler?
錢德？
I'm sorry?
你說什麼？
Look...
聽著…
I'm sure that people know you exist.
我相信他們都知道你的存在
Oh, yeah? I work in a cubicle...
是嗎？我在一個小房間工作…
surrounded by people.
四周都是人
I've been talking to you for five minutes now about killing myself...
我已經跟你談了五分鐘 我要自殺的問題…
and no one's even looked up from their desk. Hang on.
沒有人抬頭起來看我一眼，等一下
Hey, everybody...
嘿，大伙們…
I'm gonna kill myself.
我要自殺了
I got nothing.
他們不理我
Good chair.
好漂亮的椅子
Now, if anybody asks...
好了，如果有人問起…
your name is Rosita.
你的名字就叫蘿希塔
Poor thing. Cut down in her prime.
可憐的小東西，她是英年早逝
Joey, the new chair will be here in an hour.
喬伊，新椅子一小時內就會送來
Maybe we should move Rosita out of here.
或許我們該把蘿希塔搬出去
Start the healing process.
開始療傷止痛
Yeah, I guess you're right.
好吧，我猜你說的對
She's healed!
她好了！
That's weird.
那太奇怪了
No, it's not weird.
不，一點都不奇怪
It's a miracle!
這是奇跡！
It's not a miracle. I'm sure there's an explanation.
這不是奇跡 我相信這一定有合理的解釋
There is. If your heart is pure,  wondrous things can happen.
沒錯，只要你的心地純正 奇跡一定會發生
She'll understand. I didn't do it on purpose.
她會瞭解的，我不是故意的
Dad, that won't matter to her.
爸，對她來說那並不重要
Look, all my stuff is safe and dry.
你看，我的箱子完全沒事
And all her stuff is...
她的東西都…
growing new stuff.
長出新的東西了
This is the kind of thing...
就是這樣的事…
that makes her think you love me more than you lovr her.
讓她認為你們愛我更勝於愛她
Oh my God. Does she realy think that?
天啊，她真的那麼認為？
-Well, can you blame her? -I don't know.
-你能怪她嗎？ -我不知道
We may have favored you unconsciously. You were a marvel.
或許我們在潛意識裡 是偏愛你的，你是個奇跡
-The doctors said your mom couldn't.. -I don't want to hear about it.
-醫生說你媽沒辦法… -我不想聽
-Really? -Well, not right now.
-真的嗎？ -現在不想
Monica came here for some memories. Damn it, we'll give her some.
摩妮卡來這裡找回憶 該死，我們得給她一些回憶
Okay, grab...
好吧，拿…
Grab some boxes. We'll take stuff from mine...
把空箱子拿過來 我們拿一些我的東西…
and whatever we can pass off as hers, we'll put in there.
放在這些箱子裡 只要能騙過她的就行
Like, this. She could have made this.
譬如說這個，這可能是她做的
-This could have been hers. -Sure.
-這可能是她的 -沒錯
If you want to tell the medical marvel story while we work, that'd be fine.
現在是告訴我那個「醫學奇跡」 的適當時機了
I am so psyched I kept this chair for myself.
我好高興我能把這張椅子 留下來給自己用
Yeah. Me too.
對，我也是
You know, this thing has speakers in the headrest?
你知道這張椅子的頭墊上 還附了喇叭嗎？
-No, really? -Yeah.
-不，真的嗎？ -沒錯
You can hook it to the TV and you get radio.
你可以把它跟電視機接在一起 還可以聽收音機
My chair heals itself.
我的椅子有自療的功能
All right. Let's just forget about the people at the office, okay?
好吧，我們別提 辦公室的同事了，好嗎？
There's gotta be someone worth sticking around for.
一定有人值得你留戀
What about family or friends? Maybe a girlfriend?
你的家人跟朋友呢？ 或許你有女朋友？
Yeah, right.
是啊
Oh, sorry. Boyfriend?
喔，抱歉，你的男朋友呢？
Okay, I should...
好了，我應該…
be getting back to my thing now.
去做我想做的事了
See you.
再見
I'm not finished! Don't you dare hang up on me!
我還沒有說完！你休想掛我電話！
The new girl's good.
新來的女同事真的有一套
Which boxes are mine?
哪些箱子是我的？
-These are yours right here. -Okay.
-你的箱子在這裡 -好吧
A coloring book.
著色簿
You loved that thing.
你喜歡那個玩意
You never went anywhere without...
你去哪裡都會…
without that coloring book.
都會帶著那本著色簿
Really?
真的嗎？
Looks like I had trouble staying in the lines.
看起來我老是沒辦法 把顏色塗在線裡
Nuh-uh!
不
Wow, look at this.
哇，你看這個
I can't believe I even fit into this shirt.
我不敢相信以前我穿得下這件T恤
（暴龍 羅斯）
Oh, this is yours.
喔，這是你的
I don't know how that got in there.
我不知道它怎麼會跑到那裡去
Hey, this isn't my stuff.
嘿，這不是我的東西
Ross, these are your boxes.
羅斯，這些是你的箱子
Where are my boxes?
我的箱子在哪裡？
The garage flooded, sweetie, and ruined your boxes. I'm sorry.
車庫淹水，親愛的 你的箱子都進了水，對不起
Just mine?
只有我的箱子進水了？
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是那樣的
Why wasn't Ross' stuff ruined?
為什麼羅斯的東西都沒壞？
I used your boxes to divert water away from the Porsche.
我用你的箱子擋水來保護我的保時捷
Ross' stuff is fine,  but I have no memories...
羅斯的東西都沒事 但我什麼回憶都沒有了…
so you could keep the bottom of your car from water?
只為了你不希望 你的汽車底盤碰到水？
There was also leaves and gook and stuff.
水裡有樹葉、泥巴跟雜物
I can't believe this!
我不敢相信！
Screw it. I'm having one.
去他的，我要抽根煙
-Hey, Chandler. -Hey.
-嘿，錢德 -嘿
How'd you like to sit in a chair that reclines...
你要不要試試看一張可以平躺…
has a rolling massage...
有滾輪按摩功能…
and speakers in the headrest?
頭墊還附了喇叭的椅子？
I've tried that so many times...
我試過很多次…
they won't even let me in the store anymore.
但他們已經不再讓我走進他們店裡
What if I said you could do it in my apartment?
如果我說你可以到我家試坐一下呢？
Are you telling me...
你是說…
you bought the chair that makes all others obsolete?
你買了那張讓其他椅子 都變成廢物的椅子？
The chair that Sit Magazine called "Chair of the Year"?
那張《椅子雜誌》封為 「年度最佳椅子」的椅子？
I just purchased...
我剛剛買了…
the La-Z-Boy E-Cliner 3000.
懶男孩E傾斜3000型
Well, that's awesome! That's great! What made you do it?
喔，那真的是太棒了！太帥了！ 你為什麼會買下它？
It's a long story, but,  I broke Joey's chair..
說來話長，但我弄壞了喬伊的椅子…
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You broke Joey's chair?
哇…你弄壞了喬伊的椅子？
I thought I did, that's why I replaced it with mine.
我以為是我幹的 所以我用我的椅子跟它調包
That's how it got fixed!
所以它才會完全沒事！
You thought that elves came in and fixed it?
你以為是妖精把它修好的？
No.
不
Angels.
是天使干的
I'm getting my chair back.
我要把我的椅子拿回來
Well, looks like it wasn't healed after all!
喔，看起來它根本沒有自療功能！
I guess this chair's mine now.
我猜這張椅子是我的了
Joey, you broke my chair!
喬伊，你弄壞了我的椅子！
Your chair?
你的椅子？
He thought he broke it,  so he switched chairs.
他以為他把它弄壞了 所以他調換了椅子
So there was no miracle?
奇跡根本不存在？
No, Joe. No miracle.
沒錯，喬伊，奇跡不存在
Oh, no! This is devastating!
喔，不！這真的是太糟糕了！
My faith is shaken. I'm glad I have a new chair to get me through this.
我的信念被擊垮了，我很高興 這張新椅子能陪我走過這一切
Where can I find Earl? He's the supply manager here.
請問厄爾在哪裡？他是總務部經理
I don't know any Earl.
我不認識厄爾
I'm right here!
我在這裡！
Earl?
厄爾？
I'm Phoebe.
我是菲比
Phoebe?
菲比？
The lady who sells toner?
賣碳粉的小姐？
Look, you can't kill yourself.
聽著，你不能自殺
Look, I really appreciate you coming down..
我很感激你趕過來…
No, I can't let you do it.
不，我不能讓你那麼做
-Why? -Because, fate made me call you today.
-為什麼？ -因為命運讓我今天打電話給你
I thought it was toner.
我還以為你是打電話來賣碳粉
Think about it, okay? This isn't even my regular job.
好好想一想，好嗎？ 這根本不是我的正職
My first day, you're my first call.
我第一天上班就第一個打電話給你
Somebody else may have hung up, but I wouldn't do that...
其他人可能會掛掉電話 但我不會那麼做…
because I know about this stuff.
因為我瞭解這種事
-My mom killed herself. -Really?
-我媽是自殺的 -真的嗎？
How?
她怎麼自殺的？
I'm not gonna give you tips.
我絕不會教你
Don't you see that this...
你看不出來…
all came together so I could stop you from doing this?
這些都是注定好的 所以我才會來阻止你自殺？
-Couldn't it just be a coincidence? -No, it's fate.
-這不是巧合嗎？ -不，這是命中注定
It doesn't really seem like enough to be fate.
它看起來不像是命中注定
Oh, well.
喔，好吧
Okay, here's a weird thing.
好吧，有件事很奇怪
My mother was also a supply manager.
我媽媽也是總務部經理
I'm actually the office manager.
事實上我是辦公室經理
Oh, my God! So was she!
我的天啊！她也是！
And get this, okay.
還有這個，好吧
Your name is Earl, right? Her name was Pearl.
你是厄爾，對吧？她叫做普厄兒
Puh-Earl.
普…厄爾
Was there anything else?
還有別的證據嗎？
Sure.
當然有
Where're you from?
你是哪裡人？
-Philadelphia. -Oh, my God, so was she!
-費城 -喔，我的天啊，她也是！
I've got goose bumps.
我都起雞皮疙瘩了
Really?
真的嗎？
I'm wearing layers, and it's warm.
我穿太多了，而且這裡很熱
These jerks might not care about you...
或許這些混蛋不在乎你…
but the universe does, and that says a lot.
但宇宙在乎你，那才是最重要的
Did you hear that?
你們聽到了嗎？
I don't need you guys to care about me...
我不需要你們在乎我…
because the universe cares!
因為宇宙在乎我
The whole universe!
整個宇宙在乎我！
I really wish they'd care a little bit.
我真的希望他們能在乎我一下
Oh, this is terrible.
喔，這真的是太可怕了
Everything is destroyed.
所有的東西都毀了
Look at this.
你看這個
It meant enough for me to save, and now I can't tell what it is.
它一定很重要我才會保存它 現在我看不出來它是什麼東西
It's still soft.
它還軟軟的
What do you think this is?
你覺得它是什麼呢？
I think it was a mouse.
我想它是老鼠
-How are you, honey? -How do you think I am?
-你還好嗎？甜心 -你覺得呢？
You've wrecked my childhood memories...
你毀了我的童年回憶…
you love Ross more than me.
你們愛羅斯比愛我多
And I just rubbed a dead mouse on my face.
我剛剛還拿死了的老鼠碰我的臉
Sweetheart, we love you just as much as Ross.
甜心，我們愛你就像我們愛羅斯
I'm sorry about what happened...
箱子的事我很抱歉…
and I probably can't make it up to you...
也許我永遠沒辦法補償你…
but here's a start.
但這是個開始
-What's this? -It's the key to my Porsche.
-這是什麼？ -我的保時捷的鑰匙
Well, the key to your Porsche.
你的保時捷的鑰匙
What?
什麼？！
What?!
I've considered getting rid of it. I saw my reflection the other day.
我一直想把它賣掉 有天我在車子看到自己的倒影
Your mother's right, I do look like an ass.
你媽說的對，我看起來像個癟三
You're giving it to me? You're kidding.
你要把它送給我？你一定是在開玩笑
Well, wait a minute.
等一下
A couple of stupid boxes get wet, and she gets a Porsche?
幾箱蠢東西濕掉了 她就可以拿到保時捷？
-Let's take a drive? -All right!
-我們去兜個風吧 -太帥了！
What about me? I'm a medical marvel!
我呢？我是醫學奇跡！
Hey, guys.
嘿，你們都在
Have you seen Chandler's chair?
你們看到錢德的椅子了嗎？
Joey broke it. He got rid of it.
喬伊把它弄壞了，於是他把它丟了
Are you kidding? I get a Porsche and the Barcalounger's gone?
你在開玩笑嗎？我得到了保時捷 而且巴卡蘭格被丟掉了？
This is the best day ever!
這是有史以來最棒的一天